hi today we're going to talk about
prudential insurance company of america
and lump sum buyouts or settlements
offered by prudential
and today to talk with me is attorney
stephen jessup how are you steve i'm
doing well craig yourself
doing well thank you and prudential
recently
was a company that didn't do many lump
sum buyouts
um but we've been seeing a lot more
recently why do you think that is and
what's been your experience with
prudential buyouts as to why it is it
may be just a matter of now the way
they're assessing their you know their
business structure and their plan
towards it
um they do have their own separate
department that does handle it
there's individuals whose job is to do
calculations
run actuarial charts all those types of
things and uh
the experience i find with prudential is
usually rather direct
from our standpoint and that they don't
tend to drag it out if they are there is
an interest they are effectively trying
to negotiate those amounts
and they'll also be one of the the
insurance companies that's most prompted
tell you that a certain person isn't a
candidate
because they're very very selective on
the cases that they will offer any type
of a lump sum buyout on
so i think it's important for people
considering a buyout with prudential to
understand that
the disability insurance company is not
obligated to offer a buyout it's
something that they
do voluntarily if they're interested and
it's very rare that a claimant could
just call up and say hey i want to buy
out
and prudential will respond to them so
i don't think a lot of people know that
that this is one of the services that we
regularly
offer where we have contacts at
prudential where we reach out to them
for buyouts and we only do it on
situations where
we think someone would be a candidate so
what kind of criteria are you looking
for
when it comes to a person who contacts
us to determine whether or not they
might be eligible for a buyout
uh first and foremost i think it's how
long you've been on claim if you've only
been on claim a couple months
there's really unless there's some
extraneous outside facts
it's not going they're not going to be
interested in offering a buyout
they at least want to see some type of
change into the occupational change from
own occupation
any occupation if there's potential
workers compensation benefits that you
might be receiving
or going to be receiving social security
anything that can be offset under the
policy
they're going to want to see that those
items are already in place
um you know before they even start to
consider it
and also like other insurance companies
and i feel from my experience
prudential does do it more so they do
take a much more in-depth look
at the actual medical condition
unfortunately it is a business
they are determining risk and certain
conditions
are more likely to you know end to some
potentially dying before the end of the
policy
so they also take a lot of these factors
into it as well
um and that can also cause devaluation
of the policy
if they even want to offer you a buyout
so with my experience with prudential
it's a much more
in-depth uh mathematical you know review
of the claim
i i tend to find that the offers are
fair from them but it varies based upon
what the prevailing interest rate is
sometimes they may their interest rates
may be higher than what the market rate
is compared to other companies and
that's a
disadvantage for a claimant that's a
technical matter that we could discuss
with anyone who calls us
also the mortality issues in terms of
whether or not they think claimant's
going to not
is going to die before age 65
is also a factor so there's lots of
factors to consider
if you're interested in a lump sum
buyout with prudential and it's possible
every now and then they send a letter
out to someone saying if you're
interested let us
you know to contact them we recommend
that you give us a call we'll offer you
a free consultation
we'll review your entire claim with you
and we'll let you know if we think that
you would be
a good candidate for a buyout and we'll
let you know right away whether or not
we would be able to assist you